# SANDIP THAPA

Tinthana-14, Chandragiri, Bagmati Province, Nepal sandipthapa386@gmail.com (+977) 9808976977

A highly motivated and hard-working individual, graduate of Computer Science with about 2 years of active participation on web development using React.js & Next.js. Wide range of technical skill-set and attention to detail. Loves to work as a Frontend Developer where I could create digital magic and elevate user interface and experience to the next level.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**JAN 2022 - PRESENT** 

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

- Convert Figma designs into web pages using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Develop new user-facing features using React.js and Next.js with Typescript.
- Develop and maintain fast, bug-free, and re-usable components for the in-house product.
- Collaborate with design team to enhance user interfaces and its experience.
- Implement and manage version controlling of the project using git flow.

**SEPT 2021 - DEC 2021** 

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - INTERNSHIP, EKBANA SOLUTIONS PTE. LTD.

- Developed supermarket app with React.js.
- API integration and data handling using Context API.
- Got to learn about Software Development Life Cycle using SCRUM.

### **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2021

BSc (Hons) IT, HERALD COLLEGE, UNIVERSITY OF WOLVERHAMPTON

- Introduced to fundamentals of programming.
- Introduced to Data Structure and Algorithms.
- Introduced to Database Management Systems.
- Assigned to multiple mini and group projects.
- Worked on different research, communication and collaboration skills.

2016 - 2018

INTERMEDIATE - SCIENCE, KATHMANDU BERNHARDT COLLEGE

Majors: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science

## **PROJECTS**

**JUN 2022 - PRESENT** 

Homaale, Associated with CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

Technologies: Next.js, Typescript, Redux, Styled-components, Mantine, Axios, Formik, React Query, Google Maps, Docker

<u>View Project</u> ☐

**JUL 2023** 

ExerGym - Gym exercise app

Technologies: React.js, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Rapid API (ExerciseDB)

View Project 2

**APR 2022 - JUN 2022** 

Car Hub - Car showcase app

**Technologies**: Next.js(SSR), Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Rapid API (Cars by API-Ninjas)

View Project

**APR 2022 - JUN 2022** 

**Cagtu Nepal,** Associated with CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

Technologies: Next.js(SSG, ISR), Typescript, SCSS, Docker

View Project 2

## **KEY SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS3/SCSS/Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap5
- Javascript
- TypeScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- React Query
- Mantine UI
- Yup

Formik

- Git
- Gitlab
- Docker Figma

- SCRUM
- Communication
- Team Work Critical Thinking
- Leadership

**SOCIAL ACCOUNTS** 

 Portfolio: https://www.sandipthapa.com.np/

• LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandipthapa99/

• Github: https://github.com/sandipthapa99/